Association of Liberated Librarians Records 157
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
- Series 8: Site Visits
  - USA Today (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Draft letter from Mary Feldman to Barbara Maxwell requesting visit to USA Today library, 29-Oct-96 (Item 2)
    - Draft letter from Mary Feldman to Bruce Rosenstein regarding visit to USA Today bara Maxwell requesting visit to USA Today library, 4-Dec-96 (Item 3)
    - Bruce Rosenstein Business Card, undated (Item 4)
    - Handwritten notes, undated (Item 5)
    - Draft announcement of visit to USA Today Newsroom and library on December 9, 1996, 12/9/1996 (Item 6)
    - Announcement of December 9, 1996 visit to USA Today, 9-Dec-96 (Item 7)
    - Letter from Bruce Rosenstein to Mary Feldman dated November 5, 1996 confirming visit to USA Today, 11/5/1996 (Item 8)
- Series 9: Peripheral Organizations
  - ALA Ephemera (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Poster of quote from President Eisenhower to 1953 ALA Conference in Los Angeles (Item 1)
    - Invitation to dinner IHO Dr. Elizabeth Stone as ALA Vice-president Elect, February 3, 1979, 2/3/1979 (Item 2)
    - ALA Membership survey undated (Item 3)
    - 1998 ALA Awards Banquet brochure dated 6/30/1996 (Item 4)
  - DCLA Executive Board 5/69-5/71 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Meeting minutes from DCLA Executive Board from May 24, 1969 to May 13, 1971 in a blue canvas covered three ring binder, 24-May-69 (Item 1)
  - DCLA Guide to Officers 1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - DCLA Guide to officers and chairpersons July 1982, Jul-82 (Item 1)
  - DCLA Guide to Officers 1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - DCLA Guide to officers and chairpersons July 1986, Jul-86 (Item 1)
  - DCLA Handbook 1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - DCLA Handbook 1987-1988 in a maroon three-ring folder (Item 1)
  - DCLA Handbook 1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - DCLA Handbook 1990-1991 (Item 1)
  - DCLA Interfaith Library Committee 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - original map and proposed itinerary for October 1, 1967 visit, 10/1/1967 (Item 1)
    - draft description of the Interfaith Library Committee, undated (Item 2)
    - Letters between Mary Feldman and St Pius Parish Library October 13, 1969 (Item 3)
    - Letters between Mary Feldman and Chevy Chase Presbyterian Church October 14,1969 (Item 4)
    - History of library at Chevy Chase Presbyterian Church dtd August 1969, Aug-69 (Item 5)
    - Invitation to 2nd Cchurch and Synagogue Library Tour October 6, 1968 (2 copies), 6-Oct-68 (Item 6)
    - The Virginia Churchman, December 1968, Interfaith Library Tour, Dec-68 (Item 7)
    - Washington Post, Sept 28,1968. Tour Slated In Libraries of Churches, 28-Sep-68 (Item 8)
    - The Jewish Week, April 27, 1967. Library services are offered., 27-Apr-67 (Item 9)
    - Northern Virginia Sun, Sept 28, 1968. Interfaith Tour of Libraries Is Planned Here on Oct. 6y, 28-Sep-68 (Item 10)
    - Radio Spot Announcement. DCLA Interfaith Library Tour. RElease after Sept 27., 27-Sep-68 (Item 11)
    - Letter between Mary Feldman and Trinity College Library regarding tour dtd March 21, 1969, 21-Mar-69 (Item 12)
    - Postcard note from Ralph Wilbur to Mary Feldman, postmarked Jan 10, 1969, 10-Jan-69 (Item 13)
    - Library of Congress Information Bulletin, Vol. 27, No. 39. p. 582 article on 2nd Church and Synagogue Library Tour, undated (Item 14)
    - Letter from Margaret Korty to Mary Feldman, dtd Nov 23, 1968, 23-Nov-68 (Item 15)
    - Handwritted note, undated. (Item 16)
    - Church Library Council News, Number 33, Summer 1968, article on p. 4, Highlights from First CSLA Conference (Item 17)
    - Minutes of the Sept 8,1968 meeting of the Interfaith Library Committee of the DCLA, 8-Sep-68 (Item 18)
    - DCLA Interfaith Library Committee Library Tour, Oct. 6, 1968., 6-Oct-68 (Item 19)
    - Postcard note from Carol Raney to Mary Feldman, postmarked Jan 15,1969, 15-Jan-69 (Item 20)
    - Letter from Prince George County Chapter of Church Library Council to Mary Feldman, Jan 24, 1969, 24-Jan-69 (Item 21)
    - Second annual church and synagogue library tour, Vogel - Sept 12, 1968, 12-Sep-68 (Item 22)
    - draft article for "News Bulletin" Church and Synagogue Library Association, Spring 1968, dtd October 1, 1967, 1-Oct-67 (Item 23)
    - Minutes of the January 19th meeting of the Interfaith Library Committee, 19-Jan-69 (Item 24)
    - DC Libraries Bulletin, Vol. 40, No. 1, Winter 1969. p. 18 has note of DCLA interfaith tour (Item 25)
    - Catholic Library World, December, 1968 p. 216 has note about 2nd annual Church and synagogue library tour, Dec-68 (Item 26)
    - Letter from Carol Haney to Mary Feldman dtd Oct 23, 1967, 23-Oct-67 (Item 27)
    - Minutes from the Feb 11, 1968 meeting of the DCLA Interfaith Library Committee, 11-Feb-68 (Item 28)
    - MInutes from the Dec 3, 1967 meeting of the DCLA Interfaith Library Committee, 3-Dec-67 (Item 29)
    - Minutes from the May 19, 1968 meeting of the DCLA Interfaith Library Committee (2 copies), 19-May-68 (Item 30)
    - Membership list of the DCLA Interfaith Library Committee, undated (Item 31)
    - Handwritten note from Elizabeth Tate to Mary Feldman dated July 1,1968, 1-Jul-68 (Item 32)
    - Minutes from the March 17, 1968 meeting of the DCLA Interfaith Library Committee, 17-Mar-68 (Item 33)
    - Letter from Carol Raney to Ruth Smith dtd 5-13-1968, undated (Item 34)
  - DCLA Materials/Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - DCLA membership mailer 1989-1990 (Item 1)
    - DCLA Annual Banquet program, May 30, 1991, 30-May-91 (Item 2)
    - DCLA membership mailer 1990-1991 (Item 3)
    - brochure of 16th Annual Legislative Day, April 24, 1990, 24-Apr-99 (Item 4)
    - List of DCLA Presidents, 1894 - 1990, compiled by Shirley Loo, 1989-1990 president (Item 5)
    - DCLA membership mailer 1978-1979 (Item 6)
    - DCLA Annual Banquet program, May 21, 1976, 21-May-76 (Item 7)
    - DCLA membership brochure for 1974-1975 (Item 8)
    - DCLA Membership mailer 1984-1985 (Item 9)
    - DCLA Objectives (3rd draft) 1 page, undated (Item 10)
    - DCLA Statement of Objectives (Tentative draft -- No. 2) 2 pages, undated (Item 11)
    - DCLA Election Data - 1971 - 5 pages (Item 12)
    - July 24, 1969 Letter from Jeanne Rose, Arlington Country Libraries to Mary Feldman welcoming her to the 1969-1970 DCLA Committee on Continuing Professional Education, 24-Jul-69 (Item 13)
    - April 16, 1970 letter from Jeanne Rose to Mary Feldman on April 22, 1970 meeting of the Continuing Education Committtee (Item 14)
    - Meeting minutes and recommendations to the Executive Board from the April 22, 1970 meeting of the Continuing Education Committee, 22-Apr-70 (Item 15)
    - Minutes from the August 28, 1969 meeting of the DCLA Continuing Education Committee meeting at the Library of Congress, 28-Aug-69 (Item 16)
    - DCLA By-Laws as amended February 24, 1965, 24-Feb-65 (Item 17)
    - Clips and Quotes, Volume 3, No. 7 April, 1969, Apr-69 (Item 18)
    - Clips and Quotes, Volume 3, No. 8 May, 1969, May-69 (Item 19)
    - Clips and Quotes, Volume 4, No. 1 October, 1969, Oct-69 (Item 20)
    - Clips and Quotes, Volume 4, No. 2 November - December, 1969, Nov/Dec 1969 (Item 21)
    - Clips and Quotes, Volume 4, No. 3 January- February, 1970, Jan/Feb 1970 (Item 22)
    - Clips and Quotes, Volume 4, No. 4 March- April, 1970 (Item 23)
    - Clips and Quotes, Volume 5, No. 5 May, 1970, May-70 (Item 24)
    - Announcement of the DCLA Social Responsibilities Round Table (DC SRRT) as an official ALA affiliate (postmarked December 28, 1970), 28-Dec-70 (Item 25)
    - DC SRRT program - The Librarian in the Political Process "The art of lobbying" January 7, 1971, 7-Jan-71 (Item 26)
    - Minutes from the DC SSRT 2nd organizational meeting, undated (Item 27)
    - Minutes from the DC SSRT 3rd organizational meeting November 12, 12-Nov-70 (Item 28)
    - DC SRRT Membership List, undated (Item 29)
    - DCLA invitation to its 75th Anniversary Dinner on May 27, 1969 featuring Alex Haley as guest speaker, 27-May-69 (Item 30)
    - LC Information Bulletin Vol. 28, No. 41 October 9, 1969 note on DCLA Diamond Jubilee, 9-Oct-69 (Item 31)
    - LC Information Bulletin Vol. 29, No. 5 February 5, 1970 note on formation of DC SRRT, 5-Feb-70 (Item 32)
    - Minutes from February 24, 1969 meeting of the DCLA, 24-Feb-69 (Item 33)
    - Minutes from the April 22, 1970 meeting of the DCLA, 9-Apr-70 (Item 34)
    - LC Information Bulletin Vol. 29, No. 13, April 2, 1970 note on meeting of the DCLA Reference Roundtable, 2-Apr-70 (Item 35)
    - LC Information Bulletin Vol. 29, No 14, April 9, 1970 note on the ALA New Directions committee presentation to the DCLA on April 22nd., 9-Apr-70 (Item 36)
    - DCLA Annual Banquet, April 9, 1970 featuring guest speaker Thomas Asher, President, Maryland ACLU, 9-Apr-70 (Item 37)
    - Catalog of American Portraits - Wilford Cole, Keeper (From an interview for the Connecticut Genealogical Society), undated (Item 38)
    - Library of Congress Historic American Buildings Survey, undated (Item 39)
    - Reed, Daniel J. 1967. The Catalogue of American Portraits. Smithsonian Institution (reprinted from The American Archivist, Vol. 30, No. 3, July 1967), Jul-67 (Item 40)
    - The Historic American Buildings Survey. U.S. Government Printing Ofice: 1970 O - 373-544 (Item 41)
    - Farm Security Administration Collection, undated (Item 42)
    - Library of Congress Historic American Buildings Survey catalog and price list, undated (Item 43)
    - April 27, 1971 Transportation Dept. Library Tour (DCLA, SLA, Society of Library aned information Tecnicians, Law Libraries Society), 27-Apr-71 (Item 44)
    - February 6, 1971 DCLA program "The World of Childrens's Books", 6-Feb-71 (Item 45)
    - May 8-10, 1971 DC SRRT program on Socially Effective Xeroxing (SEX), 8-May-71 (Item 46)
    - April 28, 1971 DCLA Membership meeting announcement for May 26, 1971, 28-Apr-71 (Item 47)
    - DCLA Potomac River Cruise on June 12, 1971, 12-Jun-71 (Item 48)
    - American Airlines special charter flight to ALA in Dallas, 1971, Summer, 1971 (Item 49)
    - First area-wide Bookmobile Conference June 3, 1971., 3-Jun-71 (Item 50)
    - DCLA Election 1971 Ballot (Item 51)
    - Correspondence from 1969-1970 including DCLA By-Laws, Treasurer's Report and assorted correspondence (Item 52)
    - 1979 DCLA Annual Spring banquet, Spring 1979 (Item 53)
    - Joint DCLA/SLA Banquet featuring George Higgins, author of "A City on a Hill" a novel of Washington Politics, Spring 1979 (Item 54)
    - DCLA Planning Breakfast, July 25, 1987, 25-Jul-87 (Item 55)
    - ALA Report (undated), unnamed (Item 56)
    - DCLA selected accounts (1986-1987) (Item 57)
    - DCLA letter authorizing which members can incur expenses at a local print shop dated July 24, 1987, 24-Jul-87 (Item 58)
    - DCLA Reference Interest Group 1986-1987 (Item 59)
    - Handwritten Membership list (undated) (Item 60)
    - DCLA Committee Members July 15, 1987, 15-Jul-87 (Item 61)
    - DCLA Annual Reports for 1986-1987 Committee and interest Group Chairs (Item 62)
    - Report of the Government Documents Interest group, 1986-1987, Murray Howder, Chair (Item 63)
    - Death of Jane Brewer Amann-Jones June 12, 1987, 12-Jun-87 (Item 64)
    - Letter from Charles Brown to Mary Feldman dated 8/6/87, 8/6/1987 (Item 65)
    - Technical services interest group annual report 1986/1987 (Item 66)
    - DCLA Intellectual freedom committee note 1987-1988 (Item 67)
    - DCLA Executive Board 9/30/1982 (Item 68)
    - Letter from Doria Grimes to Mary Feldman accepting nomination to run for DCLA VP dtd 3/3/89, 3/3/1989 (Item 69)
    - Letter from Dorothy Stewart to nominating committee datad 3/13/89, 3/13/1989 (Item 70)
    - Letter from Elizabeth Knauff to nominating committee dated 2/28/89, 3/13/1989 (Item 71)
    - Letter from Murray Howder to nominating committee dated 2/26/89, 2/26/1989 (Item 72)
    - Letter from Janice Anderson to nominating committee dated 3/14/89, 3/14/1989 (Item 73)
    - Letter from Joan Higbee to nominating committee dated 2/27/89, 2/27/1989 (Item 74)
    - resume from Trellis Wright, undated (Item 75)
    - Letter from Eleanor Pourron to nominating committee dated 2/15/89, 2/15/1989 (Item 76)
    - Intercom Vol 18, No. 10 June 1989, Jun-89 (Item 77)
    - Announcement of Joint Spring Workshop, April 3, 1992, 3-Apr-92 (Item 78)
    - Membership list (9 pages) and member surveys (18), undated (Item 79)
  - DCLA Membership, Programs (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Membership brochure April 3, 1992, 3-Apr-92 (Item 1)
    - DCLA Annual Banquet Program, May 21, 1976, 21-May-76 (Item 2)
    - DCLA Annual Banquet Program, May 22, 1995, 22-May-95 (Item 3)
    - DCLA Progress Report September 1994 - May 1995 (Item 4)
    - 1998 ALA Inaugural Banquet, June 30, 1998, 30-Jun-98 (Item 5)
    - 1981/1982 DCLA Annual Spring Banquet Announcement (Item 6)
    - DCLA Membership brochure 1981-82 (Item 7)
    - DCLA 100-year anniversary Program, June 18, 1994, 18-Jun-94 (Item 8)
    - DCLA Membership brochure 1979-1980 (Item 9)
    - DCLA Membership brochure 1982-1983 (Item 10)
    - various year membership brochures, 1979-1980, 1981-1981, 1984-1985 (Item 11)
  - SLA Materials/Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - SLA Group bylaws, 1985 (Item 1)
    - SLA Chapter Manual Update, 1985 (Item 2)
    - SLA Manual of Proceddure 1985 Edition (33 pages) (Item 3)
    - List of names and addresses of retired SLA members in DC area, undated (Item 4)
    - SLA Chapter Notes - Washington DC Chapter, Vol 57, No. 5, Feb 1998, Feb-98 (Item 5)
    - SLA Guidelines 1987 (Item 6)
    - SLA Model Group Bylaws, May 9, 1988, 9-May-88 (Item 7)
    - Planning meeting for Steering committees, 9/16/1988 (Item 8)
    - Minutes of the Sept 29, 1988 meeting of the Steeering Committee, 29-Sep-88 (Item 9)
    - handwritten notes, undated (Item 10)
    - Solicitation for donations to the SLA Building Fund dated August 1984, Aug-84 (Item 11)
    - SLA Chapter notes, Novmber 1992, Annnouncement of ALL (Item 12)